Poor little thing,
小可怜哪
life is rough on you.
你真是命苦啊
Cutie,
小可爱
what are you going to do?
你可怎么办呢
What's wrong, Dad?
怎么了爸
Look at it, so pitiful.
你看它多可怜哪
It used to live in the big tank
以前呢
and was pushed around
它在大鱼缸里
by bigger fishes.
总是被别的鱼欺负
I moved it
爸爸没办法就给它养到
to this small one.
这个小缸子里来了
But your mom
可是你妈妈呢
always thinks it's a hassle.
就总是嫌麻烦
She rarely
她只记得喂大缸的鱼
feed it.
从来不喂它
Look,
你看
Hunger is damaging it.
三天两头就饿得你看
It looks lifeless.
蔫了
Your mom
你妈说
wants to give it away,
要把它送人
but I can't let it go.
可我舍不得呀
What should I do?
这可怎么办呢
Xiaoning,
筱柠啊
can you take it?
你把它拿走吧
You're the most caring.
你最有爱心了 对不
I know
爸爸相信你一定
you'll take good care of it.
会把它照顾得很好的
If you take it,
你把它拿走
I can visit it
爸爸想它的时候
when I miss it.
还可以去你那儿看看它
All right,
行
I will
那我
take it home.
回头把它带回家
Really?
真的
I'll give you
爸爸再送你一兜鱼食
some fish food too.
好不好
Take it now.
现在就拿走
Dad, why are you
爸你干吗呀
in such a hurry?
没那么着急吧
I said I will take it.
我肯定把它带回去
Before your mom
晚了你妈妈
give it away.
就把它送人了
Hurry,
快 快 快
take it now.
现在就拿走
Go, go, go.
走 走 走
I haven't eaten yet.
我还没吃饭呢
Wait,
不是
why is the fish gone?
怎么把鱼搬走了
I was about to feed it.
我正准备喂鱼呢
What fish?
什么鱼
It's been given away.
送人了
Feed what?
喂什么
Forget it.
喂 喂 喂
I... I just bought new fish food.
我 我新买的鱼食
What do you mean?
你什么意思呀
Poor thing.
你可太可怜了
Xiaoning,
筱柠
Can we talk?
想跟你好好聊聊
If it is at your convenience.
如果你愿意的话
All couples argue.
哪有夫妻不吵架的
It's normal for a couple
你说小两口有个矛盾
to have disagreements
有个意见不合
or conflicts.
那不是正常吗
If you both decide
如果你们两个
to stay together,
决定在一起过日子了
just give it your all
那就铆足了劲
and make it work.
好好过日子
Allow me.
我来吧
Take it home.
把它带回家吧
We can have the talk at home.
回家了以后再说
Did you do that on purpose?
你故意的吧
Look,
你看
actually, Yuheng
其实小纪这孩子啊
is a really good kid.
真挺不错的
Last night, he was worried
他昨儿晚上
that Xiaoning wouldn't sleep well,
怕筱柠睡不好
so he came over to bring things.
人家连夜过来送东西
To cheer her up,
又怕筱柠情绪不好
he was calling and asking questions.
电话打过来左问右问的
As parents,
咱们当父母的
sometimes we need
有的时候
to give a little push.
该推就得推一把
Just like us back then,
就像咱俩当初
if someone
那时候要是有人
had helped us,
帮咱俩一把
you know,
是吧
we would
咱俩
have avoided many detours.
少走多少弯路啊
You've said
你看看你
all the good things.
好话都让你说了
You think I don't want them to be well?
难道我不希望他们好吗
My thinking is,
我是觉得吧
if they have problems,
他们俩要是有问题
they need
那这
to talk them out.
就得说出来
Relying on gestures
你说光靠什么示好呀
and covering things up
粉饰太平
isn't enough.
那肯定是不够的呀
They need to
这个事情是不是
address and
掰开了揉碎了
clarify the issues.
得把问题说清楚才行
What is it?
什么呀
Dad,
爸
I want to talk to Xiaoning alone
我想和筱柠单独聊聊
to clear up our misunderstandings.
把矛盾说清楚
Can you help me?
您能帮我一下吗
Now you're having private chats.
你们还私聊上了
Forming little family cliques?
这搞家庭小团体啊
Last night, you and our daughter
那你和闺女昨晚上啊
had a long
聊到半夜
heart-to-heart chat
聊那么热乎
without me.
也没说带上我呀
All right,
行了
don't be jealous.
你别吃这飞醋了啊
Let's go
咱俩过去
tidy up
把那个女儿那屋
our daughter's room.
好好收拾收拾吧
It looks like
我看这个意思
she won't be coming back
今天晚上应该是
to stay the tonight.
不会回来住了
From now on,
那以后
you feed the fish.
你来喂食
I'll clean the tank, change the water.
我来洗缸和换水
The fish is mine;
鱼是我的
I can
这些事情
handle it alone.
我都可以自己做
Since it's at our house,
既然养在我们家
it's our fish.
那就是我们共同的鱼
Back then,
刚才搬鱼缸的时候
you said you had something to tell me.
你说有话要跟我说
Go ahead.
说吧
I know
我知道
you're upset about
赵方刚的事情
the Zhao Fanggang situation,
你对我有一些不满
and I need a chance to explain it.
我想再解释一下
Even though
相亲贷的事情
Zhao Fanggang didn't make
赵方刚
the decisions about the dating loan,
虽然没有决策权
he's still responsible for oversight.
不过他也有失察的责任
The knife attack incident
客户带刀
led to enormous implications.
造成的影响很大
Mr. Xing finally
邢总好不容易
found a mistake on our part,
抓到了我们的错处
and the branch manager
行长也需要
needs to have somebody account for it.
给上下一个交代
Zhao Fanggang
赵方刚这个事儿啊
must be dealt with seriously,
必须得给个严肃处理
or it wouldn't be justifiable.
要不然实在说不过去
How do you
那您打算
plan to handle it?
怎么处理啊
Either transfer him
要不就调走
or demote him.
要不就降职
Sir,
老师
you previously mentioned that
您上次也提醒我了
Mr. Xing from section two
这二部的邢总
has been looking
一直想抓住
for a way to bring down section one.
我们一部的把柄
You sent me to section one
您让我去拓展一部
to turn things around
不就是为了扭转局面
and protect it, right?
保住拓展一部吗
Sacrificing him
处理他呀
is to protect section one.
就是为了保住一部啊
Xing might
小邢那个人
escalate this
他说不定就给你
to higher-ups.
捅到上边去了
If that happens, the situation
那真到那时候
could become even harder to manage.
恐怕局面更难收拾
If you want to
如果您想要
protect section one
保住拓展一部
and ensure
想要让一部
its development,
有更好地发展
I can't
只靠我一个人
do it alone.
是远远不够的
I need him,
我需要他
and he's capable.
而且他也有这个能力
Sir, I have an idea.
老师我倒是有一个想法
Would you like to hear it?
要不您听听
Go ahead.
你说
Perhaps we can give him a stern warning
或许我们可以小惩大诫
by publicly criticizing him
给他一个
within the department
全部门通报批评
and taking away a few of his clients.
然后再拿走他几个客户
Everyone in banking knows
干银行的人都知道
the importance
贷款大户
of major loan clients
对于一个客户经理来说
to a client manager.
的重要性
This might
说不定这样
be enough to satisfy everyone.
也可以服众的
A 30%
本月扣
bonus deduction this month
百分之三十的奖金
and handover of five clients.
再移交五个客户
As for Li Xiang's tardiness, I wasn't
另外李想打卡的事情
trying to make things difficult for him.
我也不是故意去为难他
Every time I arrive,
每次都是一大早来
nobody's there.
来的时候人都不在
If this continues,
这样下去
I don't know how
我都不知道还要
to keep collaborating with Dairui.
怎么跟代瑞合作下去
Please don't be upset.
您先别生气
I understand your frustration.
我特别理解您的不满
On behalf of Mr. Li,
我代表李经理
I apologize.
向您赔礼道歉
You drove here
您今天一早
this morning, right?
是开车过来的吧
Yes.
是
Tomorrow,
这样
I'll have Mr. Li send you
明天我让李经理
one of our bank's
给您送过去一张
co-branded fuel cards
我们行里的联名加油卡
as an apology.
表示歉意
All right.
好
Take care.
慢走啊
That client was really angry and
所以那个客户很生气
wanted to file a complaint against him.
想要去投诉他
It's rare for a credit manager
管信贷的客户经理
to get customer complaints.
是很少会被客诉的
If it happens,
如果真的发生了
he might
他可能面临的
get transferred.
就是被转岗
You can
那这些话
tell me this,
你可以跟我说
or you can tell everyone.
也可以跟大家说啊
This is how you are.
你这个人就是这样
I know,
我知道
I tend to keep things to myself.
不长嘴
Since you're telling me,
那你既然跟我说出来了
does it mean...
是不是就说明
I'll definitely work hard
我一定会
to change these bad habits.
努力改掉这些坏习惯
"Work hard" is something
努力这种话
you tell yourself.
是说给自己听的
I'm result-oriented.
我只看结果
Why are you smiling?
笑什么
Didn't you
这不是
say this yourself?
都是你自己说的话吗
I'll do what I say.
我会说到做到
But I hope
不过我希望
you do the same.
你也一样
Me?
我也一样
What about me?
我怎么了
I hope
我希望
you don't give up
你不要随便
on this relationship easily.
放弃这段关系
My mom told me
我妈跟我说过
that every relationship needs
每段感情都有一段
a period of running-in.
需要相互磨合的时间
Even though we're not married,
虽然我们两个没有领证
it's normal
但是也在这段关系里
to have
出现一些矛盾
some conflicts.
也是很正常的
I'm not someone who gives up
我不是那种
when faced with difficulties.
遇见困难就放弃的人
Don't worry.
你放心吧
Since it's in our home now,
它既然来我们家了
should we
我们要不要
give it a name?
给它起个名字呀
Sure.
好啊
How about Little White?
叫小白
Little White?
小白
Doesn't it sound nice?
不好听吗
What if
那万一要是
it's a girl?
一个小姑娘怎么办
How about
要不
Nemo?
尼莫
All right,
行吧
let's go with your choice.
那就听你的
Since you named it,
你给它起名字了
changing the water
那么以后
and cleaning the tank
换水 洗缸
will still be your job.
就还是交给你吧
No problem.
没问题
In addition to follow up
除了我们刚刚提到的
with our premium clients,
优质客户的跟进之外
for the next three months,
未来的三个月
I want you
我希望
to focus on
我们大家的工作重心
marketing of
还是要放在
new clients.
新客户的营销之上
I've sent
推荐的那些客户名单
the recommended client list
在会前我已经发到了
to your work emails.
各位的工作邮箱
Are you feeling unwell?
身体不舒服呀
Mr. Zhao?
赵经理
Are you talking to me?
你在跟我说话啊
Yes, about new client marketing.
新客户的营销
Punching in at 8:30
一大早八点半打面卡
made me anxious,
搞得我有点紧张
and I didn't sleep well last night.
昨天晚上都没休息好
But you're right,
不过你提醒得对
I might be coming down with something.
好像是有点感冒了
I'll take some medicine later.
回头我得去吃点药
When I
我这人啊
don't sleep well,
只要没睡好
I don't have energy for anything.
干什么都没有精神
Everyone,
客户资料
review the client info quickly.
各组抓紧时间了解一下
If your clients
如果手上的客户有新的
have new loan needs,
贷款需求的话
follow up with them.
记得跟进
If you have any questions or ideas,
有任何问题和想法
come to my office.
可以来办公室找我
Meeting adjourned.
散会吧
Mr. Fang, with due respect,
方总您听我说啊
the loan rates at Dairui
我们代瑞这边贷款
are much lower
已经是
than our competitors.
比同行低很多的了
Hello, Mr. Fang?
喂 方总
Hello?
喂
Mr. Zhao.
赵经理
What's up?
什么指示
You'll handle the
晨跃集团的项目
Chenyue Group project.
你来负责吧
They need
他们眼下
a loan,
有一个贷款需求
and other banks
其他几个银行
are vying for it,
也都在争取
but I believe
但我相信
they will be more interested
他对代瑞给出的条件
in Dairui's terms.
更感兴趣一些
A big group.
大集团
A good work.
好活儿
I can't do it.
干不了
Mr. Ji,
纪总
Jing has been
晨跃这个项目
handling the
好像我们静姐
Chenyue project,
一直在跟进着
but I'm not sure
但具体到哪一步了
of the details.
我确实也不太清楚
Mr. Ji,
纪总
a sincere reminder:
真诚地提醒一句
section one
拓展一部
is not the Compliance Dept,
不是内控合规部
and you're not here
你也不是来这儿
to inspect.
检查工作的
Relax a bit
眉头舒展一点
and get along with everyone.
和大家相处松弛一点嘛
It's time
确实
for a change in approach.
该换个思路了
Fanggang.
小赵哥
Coffee.
咖啡
Thanks.
谢谢
Is it good?
好喝
Xiaoning, your coffee-making skills
小涂你的手艺
have leveled up.
再上新台阶啊
If that Ji guy
要是哪天你也被
ever gives you a hard time,
姓纪的那个人针对了
just open
你就出去
a café
自己开个咖啡馆
and ask Jing for a loan.
找你静姐给你批贷款
Fanggang,
小赵哥
are you planning to
你还打算
keep butting heads with Mr. Ji?
跟纪总这么僵持下去啊
It's not that I want to,
不是我想跟他僵持下去
he's the one tripping me up.
是他先给我使绊子
Don't side with him.
你可别向着他啊
I'm not siding with anyone.
我可没有向着谁啊
I mean,
我的意思是说
work
工作吗
is work.
是自己的
If...
你说万一要
What "if"?
哪有什么万一啊
I haven't been late, haven't left early,
我又没迟到又没早退
haven't disappeared.
没有玩失踪
The most I've done
顶多就是拒绝了
is refusing an unsuitable task.
不合适的工作
Can he fire me
他还能因为这个
for that?
把我给开了
Do you think I'm stupid?
你当小赵哥傻啊
I see through Ji Yuheng.
我看穿纪昱恒了
There's no way
他处处针对我
he'd
怎么可能把晨跃
give me the Chenyue project.
好心交给我做
He's probably
指不定啊
set a trap for me
在哪挖了个坑等我跳
so he can pin something on me
然后再给我安个罪名
and get rid of me.
顺理成章把我送走
The more I do,
我现在
the more mistakes I'll make.
就是做多错多
It's best to do nothing.
最好是啥也别干
I don't think he's targeting you.
我觉得他没有针对你
He's not as bad as you say.
他也没有你说得那么坏
He's just
他这个人做事情
straightforward
就是比较直接
and doesn't consider
说话的时候
others' feelings
不太考虑别人感受
when he speaks,
说话不好听
but he's a good person.
但是他人是好人
He is.
绝对的
You are siding with him.
还说没向着他
Xiaoning,
小涂
from what you're saying,
那听你这话说着
you seem
好像
to know Mr. Ji quite well.
对我们纪总很了解呀
I... I'm just guessing.
我 我瞎猜的
We all work in the same department.
咱们都在一个部门工作
If things are a mess,
弄得乌烟瘴气的
it doesn't benefit him either.
对他也没什么好处吧
Weren't you
晨跃不是
handling Chenyue?
你一直联系着吗
You take it.
你去做
I need you
不是我做什么
to tell me
不做什么
what to do?
我用你给我安排吗
Jing,
静姐
if you take the project,
你要去做的话
can I come along?
能不能带上我呀
I'm willing to do anything.
我做什么都行
I just want to learn.
我就是想多学学业务
I have an exam coming up.
马上就要考试了
If I don't pass this time,
我这次还考不过的话
I won't get permanent contract.
转正就没希望了
You want to make a leap
这么短的时间内
in such a short time?
就想要飞跃啊
Let me tell you,
我跟你讲
don't rush.
不要急于求成
Steady progress is key.
要稳扎稳打
Otherwise,
要不然
mistakes will be
未来只有靠犯错
your only teacher.
才能给你上课
Are you mocking me?
你讽刺我就讽刺我
Why are you
干吗打击
discouraging Xiaoning?
小涂的积极性啊
She just wants to learn from you.
人家想跟着你学还有错
I'm just
我只是
being honest with her.
实打实的在告诉她
There are no shortcuts in the workplace.
职场没有捷径
Don't try to run
不要还没有学会走
before you can walk.
你就想学会跑
What if you fall,
万一摔跟头怎么办
right?
对吧
And remember,
而且呢
as long as
姐再告诉你一句
you're competent,
只要你能力够强
no one can push you out.
没有任何人能把你挤走
Understand?
明白吗
That's not always true.
那可说不好
Even the upright
身正
fear schemes from petty people.
也怕小人下套
If that's the case,
那照你这么说的话
the petty person
那个小人
should be easy to catch.
坏得好像还挺简单的
It should be
应该
easy to find his faults.
很好抓他的把柄吧
He's a wolf in sheep's skin.
他是披着羊皮的狼
Rao Jing,
饶静
guess you want Ji Yuheng
你是不是特想
to get rid of me
我被纪昱恒整走
and leave some dirt for you to use,
最好再留个小辫让你抓
so you can
你黄雀在后
profit from it?
坐收渔翁之利
That's wishful thinking.
想得倒挺美的
Do I need
就这点心思
to say it out loud?
还用得着说出来吗
But Zhao Fanggang,
不过赵方刚
your narrow mind
你的那个心眼
and limited vision
还有你那个格局呀
are as small as a pinhole.
就像那个针眼一样小
Tiny.
这么小
What do you mean?
你什么意思
Xiaoning,
小涂
am I narrow-minded?
我心眼小吗
Fanggang,
小赵哥
I have something to do.
我还有事
Go ahead.
你去吧
I'll be leaving.
我先走了
Thanks, everyone.
感谢大家
See you there.
到时候不见不散
What's there to celebrate?
有什么好庆祝的呀
He left
走的时候
without hesitation,
不是挺潇洒的吗
and now
现在突然
he's making a grand return?
还杀回来一个回马枪
Is there really
难道是什么
something worth celebrating?
值得庆祝的事儿吗
Qi Yu
齐郁呢
never
一直都不是
liked crowds.
爱凑热闹的性格
I bet
我怀疑
someone else organized this.
可能是别人组织的
Who else?
还能有谁啊
It must be your ex, Lu Sijing,
不就是你那个突然诈尸
suddenly showing up.
前男友陆思靖吗
Keep your voice down.
小点声
Those two
依我看啊
are like
这俩人就是
peas in a pod.
一条裤子穿不出两种人
No wonder they're such good friends.
怪不得能成为好哥们
What do you think,
你怎么想啊
are you going?
去不去啊
No,
不去
I don't want to see him.
我才不想见到他
And he had the nerve
这俩人还好意思
to tag us.
提醒我们
Just ignore him,
你就当没看见
pretend you didn't see it.
别理他
See you this weekend,
周末见
Xiaoning and I will be there.
我和筱柠一起
What are you doing?
你干吗
Why be afraid?
怕什么呀
We're not the ones who broke promises.
背信弃义的又不是我们
If they can
他们俩都敢舔着大脸
show their faces,
在那儿晃荡
why should we hide?
我们就应该躲着藏着
You're right.
说得也有道理
They should be the ones hiding.
应该藏着的是他们
I'm telling you,
我跟你说
let's dress up
咱俩到时候
beautifully.
打扮得美美的
It's a class reunion;
同学聚会吗
let's have fun.
怎么开心怎么来喽
Fine,
开心行
but don't drink too much.
你可千万别喝多了啊
I won't.
我不会喝多的
When have you not drunk too much?
你哪次没喝多
Sijing.
思靖
Thanks for your effort.
辛苦了
How did he change so much?
他怎么变这样了
Here, have some food.
来 你们吃
He looks different from before.
跟以前长得不一样了
Freshly grilled, try it.
刚烤的你尝尝
Everyone, eat while it's hot.
大家趁热吃啊
These peppers are nice,
这辣椒还不错
quite sweet,
挺甜的
with a rejuvenating taste.
有种美容养颜的味道
When we were at the supermarket,
我们去超市买菜的时候
Qi Yu said
齐郁说
you love grilled peppers,
你爱吃烤辣椒
so he picked them one by one.
一个一个选的
Well, I also like the supermarket.
那我还喜欢超市呢
Why didn't he bring that over?
怎么不给我推过来
Everyone's here,
咱们人齐了
let's toast to Qi Yu.
大家一起敬齐郁一杯吧
Sure.
好
He's the
本来今天
guest of honor today,
他是主角
but he's been busy the whole time.
结果一直忙活到现在
Thanks for your hard work.
辛苦了
Sorry, I'm on duty
那个实在不好意思
as a driver for my boss,
我现在给领导开车
so I'm on call 24/7
二十四小时待命
and can't drink.
不能喝酒
I'll toast
我就
with water, okay?
以水代酒行吧
You all enjoy.
你们好好喝
Why come if you can't drink?
不能喝还来干吗呀
Come on,
来
let's drink.
我们喝
What about you and Ji Yuheng?
你和纪昱恒呢
Any developments
上次婚前派对之后
after the pre-wedding party?
你们俩有什么发展呀
I can tell
我能感觉得到
he likes you.
他喜欢你
Just old classmates meeting,
就是老同学见面
nothing much.
没什么交流
Can you tell them for me?
你帮我也跟他们说一下
Sure.
好啊
Remember?
还记得吗
You loved watching us
上学那会儿
play basketball when we were in school.
你就爱看我们打篮球
The players are all here today.
也是这帮小子
Over the years,
这些年
we can still reunite.
还能聚在一起
We're getting
一个个的
worse on basketball,
球技是越来越差
yet more and more talkative.
嘴倒是越来越碎了
Watch out!
小心点
Sorry!
好
Come with us, Sijing!
一起来呀老陆
Just like old times,
还跟以前一样
let Xiaoning
让筱柠
buy us water.
给咱们买水
It's Sijing who she used to buy water for.
人筱柠是给老陆买水
Don't sponge them off.
你这也要蹭
You have fun.
你 你们玩吧
I'm off now.
我先走了
Xiaoning.
筱柠
I'm sorry.
对不起
I was supposed to come back
去年你生日的时候
and propose on your last birthday.
我本来该回来求婚的
But I was focused on
可是那个时候
improving my studies
我一心在提高自己
at that time.
继续学业
And I never let go
但我从来就没有
of what we had,
放下过我们的感情
and I haven't done anything
我也没有做过任何
wrong to you.
对不起你的事情
You don't have to explain
你不用跟我解释这些
or apologize to me.
也没有什么对不起我的
I know,
我知道
I've hurt you.
我伤害了你
And I know
我也知道
we can't go back anymore.
我们回不到过去了
But, Xiaoning,
但筱柠
have you ever thought
你有没有想过
our feelings to each other were real
我们俩这么多年的感情
after all these years.
是真实存在过的
I'm sure you haven't
我相信你也没有
completely let go either.
完全地放下吧
Otherwise, why didn't you
否则像纪昱恒
choose Ji Yuheng
那么好的条件
who is excellent
又喜欢你
and likes you.
你怎么会不答应呢
That's my business,
那是我的事
not yours.
跟你没关系
Fine.
好
We're not talking about him.
那不提他
If I didn't need to keep this
要不是这段感情
relationship a secret,
见不得光
why would I waste my time
我何必浪费大好时光
talking to you?
在这儿跟你啰嗦
Let's talk about ourselves.
说说我们之间的事情
I don't want to
我们两个的事
talk about ourselves.
就更不用说了
There's nothing I can say to you.
没什么好聊的
Looks like the arm's
看来胳膊上的伤
pretty much healed.
好得差不多了
It wasn't a serious injury anyway,
本来伤得就不是很严重
Now it's almost healed.
现在好得也差不多了
Seems like Section 1
你们拓展一部
is in a turmoil.
是不是有些不太平啊
I heard you and Zhao Fanggang
我听说你跟赵方刚
had arguments in the office.
在办公室吵起来了
It's all settled.
不过事情都已经解决了
I did have some management
这次是我在管理上
problems this time.
确实存在一些问题
I promise
我保证
it won't
以后不会再出现
happen again.
类似的情况了
The problem has been in Section 1
这个一部的问题啊
for a long time.
由来已久了
It's hard enough
让你接手
for you to take it over.
本来就是在为难你了
But I'd like to
但老师还是想
remind you.
提醒你一句
The Section 1 of BDD
这个拓展一部啊
is different from Compliance Dept.
跟内控合规部不一样
You need a teamwork.
需要的是团队作战
Only when the people are united
只有人心齐了
can the team be better led.
队伍才能更好带
I know what you mean.
我懂您的意思
I've been told
之前也有人
something similar before.
跟我说过类似的话
I'm getting old
年龄大了
and talkative.
就爱啰嗦两句
You mind my nagging?
别嫌烦啊
Of course not.
当然不会
Qi Yu.
齐郁
You have the nerve
你好意思说
to be a company driver!
你自己是司机吗
You crashed my car!
把我车都撞烂了
Cracks me up.
好好笑
Have some water.
先喝口水
Game over.
输了
I'm done.
不玩了
I'm leaving.
我要回去
Going back.
我要走了
Be careful.
慢点 慢点
Xiaoning!
筱柠
I'm here!
来啦
Look out for her.
帮忙看一下啊
Xiaoning.
筱柠
Are you alright?
没事吧
Weiyi's drunk.
惟依喝多了
You guys have fun.
要不你们先玩儿
I'll take her home first.
我先送她回家
I can take her home.
我送她就行
I wanna go home.
我要回家
I brought my car,
我开车了
and I didn't drink.
没喝酒
Okay.
行
Give me her bag.
你把她包给我
Alright, we go home.
好了回家
Go home.
回家
Hello, sir.
喂 行长
Am I going now?
现在吗
It's not far.
离这儿不远
Okay.
好 好 好
I'll be there.
我马上到
You can do your job.
那你去忙吧
I'll take her back.
我送她
Weiyi likes to sleep on her back.
惟依喜欢仰着睡
Watch out if she pukes and chokes.
万一吐了容易呛着
And give her
还有睡前
a glass of honey water before bed.
给她喝杯蜂蜜水
Don't worry.
放心吧
She's okay even to drink alone
你不在的时候
when you're not around.
她一个人喝多了也没事
It's alright.
没事
How about I take...
要不我送
Let's go home.
走了回家
Let's go.
走了 走了
Take it easy.
慢一点
Here.
走
Let's go.
走了
Alright.
行
Take care of them.
你帮着照看点
Wait.
等会儿
Xiaoning, your phone.
手机 筱柠
I'll give her.
给我吧
Don't worry.
放心
Okay.
行
Uh.
那个
Message me when you get home.
到家发消息啊
Sir.
老师
I'll wait with you a little longer.
我再陪您等一会儿吧
It'll take a while
小齐他估计
for Qi to get here.
得等一会儿才能过来
It's okay.
不用
It's after hours.
咱们下班时间
I'm not your boss.
不搞这一套
I asked you out today
我今天是把你
as a fishing buddy.
当钓友约出来的
If you do so, I won't
你要这样的话
dare to ask you out next time.
我下回怎么还敢约你
Alright.
行
I'll go first.
那我先回
Yes.
赶紧回去吧
See you, sir.
走了老师
Be careful when driving.
路上慢点开啊
Okay.
好
See you, sir.
我先走了老师
I'm going home.
我要回家
Going home.
回家 回家
Hello.
喂
Hello, Xiaoning.
喂 筱柠
Is your party over?
你们快结束了吗
I'll pick you up now.
我现在过去接你吧
No. I'm okay.
不用了 不用了
I'll just go back myself.
我自己回去就行
It's so late,
天都这么晚了
and it's easy for me to pick you up.
我过去接你们也很方便
No, really.
真不用
You can't be seen now.
你现在见不得人
Besides, Ling Weiyi's drunk.
凌惟依她喝多了
I'm taking her home first.
我先送她回家
Got to go.
我不说了啊
"Can't be seen".
见不得人
Hello, dad.
喂 爸
It's me.
是我
Do you know
您知道
where Ling Weiyi
凌惟依家的地址
lives?
在哪儿吗
I need to pick up Xiaoning there.
我去接筱柠
Could you send me the address?
麻烦您给我发一下
Here comes the cab.
车来了
Okay.
来了
The cab's here.
车来了 走
Here.
来
There.
来 来 来
Mind your head.
小心头
Take it easy.
慢点啊
Thanks for getting us a cab.
谢谢你帮我们打车啊
We can go back ourselves.
我们自己能回去
Don't bother.
不用你送
It's too late.
这时间太晚了
It's not safe for you girls to go alone.
你们两个女孩不安全
I'll escort you.
走吧
I'll tell you what.
我跟你说
Gosh.
我天
Xing City is just
星城它就是
too unprincipled.
太没有原则了
Unlike me.
不像我
You can drop us off here.
就送到这儿吧
I'm different.
我就不一样
Thanks for the escort.
谢谢你送我们回来
-Thanks. -You can go now.
谢谢啊 你回去吧
Well,
不是
she's too drunk.
她都已经喝成这样了
How about I...
要不我留
Sorry. Sorry.
不好意思啊 不好意思
You okay?
你没事吧
Why don't you take your coat off?
要不你把衣服脱下来
I'll give it back after I wash it.
我洗好了还给你
If you'll bring it over.
要是你送过来的话
Sure.
可以啊
I'll call a deliveryman.
我给你同城快递
I'd rather not, then.
那还是不用了
You'd better go now.
你先走吧
I'm afraid she would
我怕她一会儿
throw up on you again.
又吐你身上
Okay.
也行
Well, be careful.
那 那 那你小心点
Okay, okay.
好 好 好
Don't let her throw up on you.
小心她吐你啊
Be careful.
小心 小心
Take it easy.
慢点 慢点 慢点
Thanks for today.
谢谢啊
Thanks.
谢谢 谢谢
I knew you did it on purpose.
我就知道你是故意的
I'm just
我不过呢
throwing up
就是把垃圾
on the garbage.
吐在了垃圾身上
Here.
走
Drink with me.
再陪我喝点
So that's why
原来这就是
I can't be seen.
见不得人的原因
Xiaoning.
筱柠
I won't leave for a while.
我暂时先不走
Call me if you need anything.
你有什么需要随时叫我
I'm being kicked out now.
我现在这样被扫地出门
It'd be embarrassing if people saw me.
被撞见也太丢人了吧
Another one from Dairui.
又来个代瑞同事
Now I can't come out any more.
现在更加见不得人了
Weiyi.
惟依
I'm on your doorstep.
我就在你家门口
Call me if you need anything.
有什么需要给我打电话
Let's drink!
喝酒
More?
还喝呀
Don't drink too much.
你少喝点
Just a little bit.
喝一点吗
Here.
来
Drink with me.
陪我喝点
He promised
说什么一天
he would make
能够保证
video calls for at least
打一个小时以上的
an hour a day.
视频电话
You were there.
当时你也在吧
You're the witness.
帮我作证啊
But then?
结果呢
It's just like
结果还是
what I said.
被我凌惟依说中了
A long-distance
这异地恋啊
relationship is an illusion.
就真的是虚幻泡影
It's worse for two in different countries.
那也比跨国恋好吧
At least
最起码
you two had a graceful breakup.
你们两个是和平分手
But me?
我呢
I was dumped.
我可是被甩的
Right.
是噢
You're worse.
好像还是你那个比较惨
No.
不对
I'm worse.
我比你惨
You see,
你看
the fact that
这陆思靖啊
Lu Sijing is an asshole
就像今晚
is as obvious as the Moon tonight.
这夜空中的这个大月亮
It's so clear
他渣得明明白白
and leaves no illusions.
不让你有任何的幻想
You knew it's the end immediately.
也就死心了吧
But Qi Yu?
可齐郁
He's always looking miserable
他分手之前和分手之后
before and after
都表现得一副
the breakup.
可怜兮兮的样子
It always
让我这心里
makes me feel...
就总觉得
I thought
但我现在本以为
I was
我已经
recovered
好好地疗完伤
and ready
准备
for another relationship,
重返情场了
but he just suddenly showed up.
他突然又给我杀出来
Is he kidding me?
玩我呢
Alright.
好了
Stop being upset.
别想这些了
What?
怎么了
No more alcohol.
别喝了 别喝了
Are you crying?
还哭了
Alright, alright.
好了 好了 好了
Don't cry.
不哭了
Don't cry. Don't cry.
不哭了 不哭了
Xiaoning,
你说
If I'm so rich
我这么有钱
and I'm not happy,
我都不幸福
who in the world
这世界上
is happy?
到底什么人才幸福啊
Don't cry.
不哭了
You're going to be happy.
你会幸福的啊
The men.
男人吗
There are men
这世界上
all over the world.
最不缺的就是男人
Don't be upset by them.
你不要为了他们难过了
Xiaoning,
你说
when will I forget him?
我什么时候才能忘记他
Every time he shows up,
最近他每一次出现
I remember
我都会想起
the first time we met.
我们第一次见面的样子
You're the Ling
你就是下了订单
who ordered for
满世界找
a 3-step layup coach?
三步上篮教练的凌同学
Interesting.
有意思
It's the first time I see someone
我还是第一次看到
hotter than the flattering photo.
照片往反方向骗的
You're Fu?
你是傅同学
Fu Lei is my roommate.
傅磊是我室友
He's busy. He asked me to teach you.
他今天有事让我来教你
Don't worry.
你放心
I'm an
我是咱们学校的
athletic student.
体育特长生
I'm Qi Yu.
我叫齐郁
I'll take care of your
你的体育选修课
optional course of P.E.
包在我身上
You try one first and I'll see.
你先试一个我看看
Okay.
行
I'll try first.
我先来一个
How's that?
怎么样
The 3 steps of yours
你这三步
were pretty random.
挺随机啊
I wouldn't need you if I were an expert.
我要是会还要你干吗
Show me.
你试试
3-step layup
三步上篮吗
is one...
就是一
You're no better than me.
你这不跟我一样吗
Wait a sec.
等 等会儿
I'm infected by you.
被你洗脑了
Your influence is too strong.
这太魔性了
I'll show you a proper one.
好好给你整一个
How's that?
怎么样
Isn't it easy?
简单吧
Qi Yu.
齐郁
He took
他这三步啊
three steps
每一步
straight into my heart.
都能走进我的心坎里
Your relationship
你们俩这恋爱吧
has been a bit of a drama
就有点像那偶像剧
from the start.
从一开始就像
Really.
你说
It's not an order for basketball training.
你那哪是陪练订单啊
It's an order for romance.
你那就是爱情订单
Or tragic romance.
虐恋订单
Teach me how to do it.
你教教我呗
How can I pretend
怎么样才能像
he doesn't exist
你对陆思靖那样
when I see Qi Yu
我看到齐郁
like you did with Lu Sijing?
我也能够当他不存在
Teach me.
你教教我呗
When the day comes
有一天
that you don't love him anymore
你不爱齐郁了
you won't feel bad
你就不会难受了
and can pretend he doesn't exist.
你就可以当他不存在了
Maybe
可能
I have to wait for someone
我也得等到一个
like Ji Yuheng to show up, too.
跟纪昱恒一样的人吧
No.
不是的
It doesn't matter if he
你等不等到那个人
shows up.
都没关系
It's up to you.
主要看你自己
You're upset because
你现在是因为
you still have feelings
心里还有齐郁
for Qi Yu.
所以才难受
By the way.
对了
Have you made up
你跟纪昱恒
with Ji Yuheng?
和好了吧
It reminds me of my mom's thoughts.
正好跟你分享一下
She said,
我妈说呢
marriage is about
这婚姻呀
putting two
就是把两个
different people
完全不一样的人
in a room and letting them
放到一个屋子里面
bond with each other.
然后相互磨合
We're
我们俩
in a relationship for marriage.
都已经奔着结婚去了
I've decided
我决定
to get to know him
要重新好好认识他
again,
了解他
trying to
争取
get used to the life with him faster.
快一点度过这个磨合期
It doesn't sound right.
听着不太对
If you're
既然是以
in a relationship for marriage,
结婚为目的的谈恋爱
you have to be in love.
那你们得恋爱啊
You need to feel the love.
你得上头
Love him!
爱他
You need to love him!
你得爱他
Love is something
爱情这个东西
that can't be found.
真的是可遇不可求
We can just be in the relationship.
我们俩先过日子吗
Maybe one day we can feel
万一这日子过着过着
the love for each other.
爱情就来了呢
Right?
是不是
I'm waiting downstairs.
我在楼下等你
I don't think they'll run into each other.
他们应该不会碰到吧
It's been all night.
这都过了一个晚上
They must be long gone.
肯定早就走了吧
The bottle's running out of water.
快喝完了
You didn't really
你不会
wait out there all night,
真的在外面等了一晚上
did you?
都没睡觉吧
I wanted to
本来呢
go upstairs,
是想上去的
but I saw someone
但是我看
waiting down there
一直有人守在下面
and someone just coming down.
还有人从上面下来
I did know
说起来我确实
I can't be seen.
还挺见不得人的
So I had to wait there.
所以只能在下面等了
Are you talking about Lu Sijing?
你是说陆思靖吧
He's just worried
他就是担心
that I couldn't bring
我没有办法
Ling Weiyi home.
把凌惟依带回家
He insisted on escorting us.
非要跟着
But we
但是我们俩
got rid of him quickly.
很快就把他打发了
Ling Weiyi threw up all over him.
凌惟依还吐了他一身呢
But seriously.
不过说真的啊
If this happens again,
下次如果还有这种情况
you'll have to let me pick you up,
你还是要让我来接你
even if I don't show up.
就算是我不露面
You can
你呢
pretend you take a cab.
就当作是打了一个专车
Are you tired?
那你困不困啊
How about
要不
I drive?
我来开车吧
Never mind.
没关系
I can do this.
可以的
You can
你
talk to me.
陪我聊聊天
It's a good time
正好
to talk about
也可以跟我聊聊
the members in Section 1 of BDD.
拓展一部的这几个人
You were the lobby manager before,
你呢之前是大堂经理
you've seen more people.
见的人也比较多
You know people better than I do.
看人肯定比我准
You're trying to
你是想
probing for information,
在我这儿
aren't you?
打探消息是不是啊
Just say something
你就说点
that doesn't violate
不违反
your team rule.
你们团结的话
Let me know a little bit.
多少让我知道一点吧
The ones with
拓展一部呢
the most clients in Section 1
客户最多的肯定就是
are definitely Jing and Fanggang.
静姐跟小赵哥了
But they have
但是他们俩
completely different styles.
风格完全不一样
Jing is
静姐
very experienced in doing things
就是做事情雷厉风行
in a vigorous
敢打敢拼
and courageous manner.
经验丰富
If she says it can be done,
只要她说可以的事情
it can be done.
绝对能做成
We have
我们为
rolled out an integrated payroll card service
代发工资个人客户
for individual payroll agents.
推出了薪金卡综合服务
I know that your hospital
我知道咱们医院
works a lot with
与外地的医院
out-of-town hospitals.
合作比较多
So, in addition to
所以呢 我们除了提供
basic services,
基础的服务以外
we can also offer you
还可以让大家享受
a discounted service
每年十二笔异地
of 12 off-site withdrawals per year.
存取款优惠服务
And we have a green channel
并且为大家开通
for personal loans.
个人贷款绿色通道
Mr. Liu.
柳主任
I am sure
我相信呢
you will choose our bank
您看完这些资料以后
after reading this information.
一定会选择我们银行的
Because of her professionalism,
因为她的专业度
precise judgment of the market,
对于市场精准地判断
and keen insight,
以及敏锐的洞察力
she can
她呢
give her clients
既可以给客户
both professional advice
专业的意见
and
又能给客户
a sense of security.
很好的安全感
But it's risky
但是银行工作人员
for a banker
左右客户的想法
to sway a client.
其实这样风险很大的
Jing doesn't have
静姐手上
any bad debts.
可没有一笔烂账
Go on.
你继续
As for Fanggang,
小赵哥呢
he's completely different.
就完全不一样了
He can
小赵哥是
become good friends
属于可以跟客户
with his clients.
打成一片的那种
His clients trust him.
让客户非常信任他
Good news!
好消息
The loan will be approved next week.
贷款下周就能批下来
Bro,
我的哥
it's hard
这贷款好不容易
to apply for a loan.
才申请下来
Save your money
你自己省着点用
and don't waste it
就别浪费那钱
on dinner for me.
请我吃饭了
Okay, I'll call you tonight.
行 那晚上联系
I've got
我这边
a call coming in.
正好有个电话进来
Okay.
好 好 好
Bye-bye.
挂了 拜拜
Li! My sis!
李姐
How could I forget
我哪能忘啊
little Qi's birthday?
小奇过生日吗
Sure.
好 你说
Whatever you want.
尽管吩咐
From what you're saying,
听你这么说完
it sounds to me like he's mingling
我觉得这个人好像
private and company's interest.
不太有分寸感
"Mingling"?
什么叫没有分寸感呢
Mr. Ji.
纪总
He's just making friends.
他那是交朋友
It's not like
交朋友
making friends is
又没有搞什么
a dishonest practice.
歪门邪道的
If he was
他要是在中间
gaining personal profit,
有什么获益的话
you'd have found him out,
那不是被你
wouldn't you?
一查一个准吗
Good point.
说得有道理
Making friends
交朋友
is fine.
没什么问题
Excuse me.
你好
Is there an antidote for alcohol?
问一下有没有解酒药
No, sorry.
没有唉
It's in the pharmacy next door.
旁边的药店里有
But they don't start
不过他们要明早
till 8:00 a.m. tomorrow.
八点才上班
8:00 a.m.
八点
Thank you.
谢谢啊